噉我請議員介紹自己咧。第一趟提問嘅時候，因為唔好意思咧，我都唔我都唔記得盧偉國議員係邊個功能組別。
抱歉，哦，O.K.
Good morning.
Yes, welcome everybody. Thank you for the attending this informal meeting. Please note that it is only an informal meeting that between the expert group and the members of the Environmental Affairs Panel. That even though the setting that could look like a bit formal, but it is because of the sun system that we could have here.
and get everybody well heard and clearly understood by the all attendants of this informal meeting that we have this setting and
Let me introduce our guest to the members of the committee. And excuse me if I cannot pronounce your name right, because I'm not an expert in the Northern European language.
So on the the first row from the the right hand side is the Dr Lee Potts from the
Eckom， the technical manager of energy， and then the Mr Herman Huisman， the senior advisor of the RWS Environment of Netherlands， then the Mr Peter Simons， the technical director of， maybe you could help me to pronounce the name of your organisation much better than I do。
嗯。
It's it's afval energiebedrijf. It's the waste and energy company of the city of Amsterdam. Okay, the letter pad is much easier for me. So so.
And then on the second row is Professor Nicholas Famili's, with the Energy Research and Technology Council of USA, and of course Mr. Elvis Al, our Assistant Director of Environmental Protection Department, and our leaf members.
of our panel to introduce themselves when they raise their question. So the first of all, could our expert friends share with us your the insight and the good practices of the incineration?
yes。
在荷蘭，我們有十二。
waste-to-energy plants with a total capacity of 7.3 million tons a year.
And all these waste energy plants meet the requirements of the European Waste Framework Directive, so they are all called recovery facilities because they are all high efficient facilities. There is a very stringent legislation.
在荷蘭，for these facilities and this this this regulation stems from 18 1989.
At that time, we had problems with polluting waste-to-energy facilities, and we closed down five of them of these facilities. And we issued new regulations, and these regulations are still in place.
這些係同一個規例，歐盟在廢棄物焚燒條例中採納。
但 nowadays there is an IPPC directive of the European Union, and there are draft documents, best reference documents based on the best available technologies.
所以，The facilities in in Europe, they are all meeting the highest standards, and they need to have the highest standards. Otherwise, they do not get licences. And the facilities in Netherlands, they
Have been established in in in the last, so they all modernised or newly established in the last say 20 20 yeah about 20 years.
and。
For the latest facilities, there there's no public opposition for these facilities. So the one in Amsterdam, but they can explain themselves.
The extension was about 50% more than 50%. Has been done without any lawsuits, without any opposition, because of the good performance of these facilities. So citizens are not even aware that these facilities are in their neighbourhoods. They are close to the cities.
And that's the case with most of our facilities. They have been realised without any objections, without lawsuits, because they are performing well. They have a very transparent operation. They are very
Open about their operations, about the missions and so on, if available.
所以， waste energy is no issue and we even import waste from a lot of countries, from UK for instance, from Italy, Naples, which has a
bad situation regarding waste management. We import the waste and it's been incinerated in the Netherlands and there's even no objection of citizens for these imports. So it's
Of none, it's it's there is no political debate about these facilities. These are well running and well performing facilities. Thank you.
Yes, thank you. Very enviable when there's no court case and no complaint from the from the residents. And let me catch up a a little bit and introduce to everybody our simultaneous interpretation system. And on on every booth you have a earpiece like this, and you could
tuned to the the simultaneous interpretation and from English to Cantonese is Channel One and
with as original language on the floor is channel zero, so that everybody could make use of our SI surface. So the the
who will be the next guest to share with us the good practices and expertise?
Yes, Mr. Peter Simons. Yes, Herman mentioned already the the situation in in Amsterdam. Indeed, when we opened our last facility, our last plant in 2007, it went without any complaints.
It's maybe also good to show to to tell you what our approach is in this.
Because we have a long history of waste-to-energy in in Amsterdam.
But for the last plant, we we had very open communication with with all the the stakeholders, and that are the NGOs, also the the environmental department who has to give the permit.
And we also, yeah.
When we designed the plans, we also showed them our plans and we said, okay, this is the standard now. But we think we can do better. We can go, we can go for lower emissions. We can go for higher efficiency. But also, and that's important for the city of Amsterdam, because they had to, yeah, finance.
the plant in in Amsterdam, we said it will bring lower cost.
對，市民有幫助。
That is also necessary for our for our economical, and we make a profit with this plant, and this profit goes to the city of Amsterdam, and then the city of Amsterdam can decide the.
Yeah, they can decide to to lower the cost for for the citizen of Amsterdam for their waste.
disposal.
Another thing is, yeah, we never talk about the emissions is not discussion point. In the Netherlands, we are we are more discussing about other items, and that is the climate, for example.
And you see that our installation, as Amsterdam has its climate targets, they want to reduce 40% of the CO2 relative to to 1990.
Our plant can make a very big contribution to that, because we are delivering sustainable energy, renewable energy.
But also, we change the energy infrastructure in in Amsterdam from yeah gas to to district heating, for example. And we also look at steam a steam network in in the harbour area where we so that that makes also a very large contribution to the energy.
和氣候目標，的市市阿姆斯特丹。
Thank you, Mr. Simos, and.
Dr. Lee Pohs or Professor Family?
yes, professor.
thank you。
I am with Columbia University in the city of New York. We're very proud of that university. It has about sixty-two Nobel laureates over the years, and we're also proud of the work we're doing because we're working on waste management. We're one of the few universities in the world that research centres that.
related to waste management, and in the past fifteen years, we have studied all types of all means of waste management in many countries. So, specifically now about this.
about Hong Kong，啊。
香港，的階梯式廢棄物管理要求，首先，人們做盡量多的回收、堆肥，香港似乎做得很好，有48%回收，但係有3.3萬噸廢棄物係填埋。
我 look one up of those landfills, Nent, you know, Northern Territories, 2,700 a day.
所以，個project which is the which is， I'm sorry。
The project which is discussed or proposed is for one million tons. So if it's done, it would leave two point three million tons still to be landfilled. And really, that's the only choice for post-recycling waste: either landfilling or waste.
所以有2.3萬噸，仍須擔心。這1萬噸，如果通過，會產生多少？首先，會產生約600萬兆瓦時。
per year, which is enough for about 103,000 citizens of Hong Kong. The electricity, it's 100,000. It will also reduce the greenhouse gases of Hong Kong by a million tons.
And also, looking at the current rate of landfilling in the landfill I mentioned, it would conserve about.
20,000平方公尺。
平時。
of landfill space. So there is a lot of good things for that project, and usually what stops these projects in our experience is the money, is the funding, does is the gross domestic product per capita. But Hong Kong is very well there. It's about fifty thousand dollars per ton on on parity.
所以，似乎係一個匯合好多好因素 for  such a plan，所以，我係 bit surprised that there is so much discussion and apparently going for years.
Well，Hong Kong is a very unique city，definitely。the，Dr. Lee Potts。
I work with Aecom. We are acting as advisers, working with the EPD. But I'll explain a little bit what's going on in the UK, because I think kind of sets some kind of context. In the United Kingdom, we have eight energy from waste, eighteen sorry, energy from waste plants, and there are a number under construction at the moment. That's partly because the the UK has to meet quite
Stringent targets around what's called the landfill directive in terms of diverting waste away from landfill. So in the next three or four years, there'll be probably 24 energy from waste plants. They're sized in probably on average probably around 150 to 200,000 tonnes per year per plant. To give you a kind of idea of the size, we do have opposition. So we do get opposition.
That's probably a legacy thing because 20 years ago, energy from waste plants weren't very clean. They didn't perform very well. Nowadays, the thing has changed quite considerably with the introduction of the waste incineration directive. The standards are very strict with the environmental regulations in terms of permitting. That's very strict.
控制通過環境局在英國，他們密切控制管理這些設施，working with the operators.
所以，我諗，what's happening is where there is opposition, it's it's it's worked through with an education programme, talking to people, kind of removing misinformation. It's a hard process at certain places within the United Kingdom. In other places, it's very straightforward and plans facilities get built very easily. But it just varies across the across the
Country, so that's the kind of the situation for us. But what will happen eventually is probably around 30 to 35% of the MSW of of the United Kingdom will go to energy from waste plants, and we will have around 50% recycling, and then the rest will be landfill. And that's quite a considerable change because 15 years.
95% went to landfill and 5% was recycled. So within 15 to 20 years, there's quite a dramatic change in waste management within the United Kingdom.
Thank you, and let me extend our welcome to the Professor Umberto Arena from the the specialist group on waste to energy from the Second University of Naples, the Italy, and the.
We just finished the first round of the sharing of experiences and good practices from our four experts from the Netherlands, UK and United States. Would the Professor Arena want to take your time to tell us your comment on the incineration and other types of waste management?
yes, my briefly, my first warning is that.
It's important to understand that.
The zero waste solution could be a dramatic decision or not decision for Hong Kong or as for other counties.
我 come from Naples， where for a long period， about twelve years， we suffered a dramatic situation。
due to the insistence to find a zero waste approach.
Their waste only represents a desirable approach, a trend on which all waste management strategies should be based.
但不能成為策略。
If do you, if as in some cases some.
people utilises zero waste as
一 sort of management system， the only result could be an incredible problem for whole territory. We now
have in the Naples area, also now, I mean, six years after the solution of the West emergency.
200 hills of waste bales accumulated in 200 pyramids.
我係六點五萬噸。
always that way that still wait to be burnt.
所以， in my experience.
there was several times.
means zero decision.
Where the, as in your country, the organisation of recycling chain is always gone, the biological treatment can be activated. It is necessary to complete the strategy with thermal treatment.
after you have to decide which kind of thermal treatment, but this depends on
The site-specific exigence and your requirements, and if you need, as Professor Temelis told a few minutes before.
very large plant, probably the moving grate combustion solution is the best one because it's very well proven.
very well.
design and management criteria， non and utilised criteria。
large， a good possibility to make a very exact prediction of cost， investment cost and operating cost。
and also enough return of investment due to the size of the plant and the high electric efficiency.
Another things could be if you need to make a smaller plant where you would like to adjust the reduction of solid residues. In this case.
The Japanese experience in some gasification process, as the direct melting system, could be useful. This is my first impression. Thank you.啊喺度咧就記錄在案先。誒，因為咧我相信誒，無論係擴展堆填區或者係做焚化設施咧，香。
港社會都會有好多不同嘅意見。咁今日係一個非正式會議，就係同嘅專家們，因為佢哋誒五月五號到八號啱啱嚟到香港，所以我哋安排咗呢個誒非正式會議嘅會面。咁咧及後，即係如果我哋要再傾堆填區嘅擴建，或者係誒政府嚟申請做焚化設施。
嘅時候咧，我哋係一定會邀請環保團體同埋居民咧嚟誒，畀翻充足嘅時間畀各方去講翻佢哋意見。所以喺呢度就真係要記錄在案。噉啊，大家知道咧誒，如果各位係同環保團體或者係居民組織係有聯係嘅咧，亦都請話翻畀佢哋聽。即係我哋唔係淨係聽一方。
專家嘅意見，咁呢度要講翻清楚啊！噉就我請委員提問啦。
係盧偉國議員。
嗯。
This is the WK Lowe. I'm represent engineers.
從啲Engineering Functional Constituency。
嗯。
作為一個工程師，因為我。
have some knowledge of the modern incineration technology， and I visited quite a number plant in。
Japan。
啊，或者係誒一ones誒 formal treatment。
even啲 oxen啊，completely decompose。你知唔知？According to what I heard from them， I would like to as well。 Since we have two experts from Netherlands， may I ask？ Usually， what is the capacity of the plant？ Maybe you have different sizes。
what are the most common size of the incineration plant in in your country? and if I ask what is the most economical size, then what will be your answer?
and。
我聽聞其實係冇公眾反對的，即係意思係喺你哋國家，呢種焚燒廠將廢棄轉化為能源，係非常受市民歡迎嘅。
啊！
在香港，在舊 days，我們有 plan， of course， not the same kind of advanced technologies we have today， and they give out the smoke every day. Therefore, the maybe in the concept of some old citizens in Hong Kong， they still have。
That picture, you know, of those old incineration plants. The modern plants are of course are very different, but certainly this is a good opportunity to hear from the expert group this morning. Thank you.
伊斯巴德·弗蘭德林。
Yes, I already mentioned we have 12 facilities. The smallest one is 230 kilotons. 230. 230 kilotons per year.
The largest one is from my neighbour. It's about 1.4 million tons a year.
So there's a big range. There is an economy of scale, especially due to, but I think Peter can explain more of that.
But economic size varies. But what's also very important about the economy of these facilities is whether you have an outlet for your steam and electricity.
And that's one of the main elements in well the the the.
這些、這 economy of these facilities， most of them are next to either industrial areas or urban areas, cities.
where the steam of these facilities is transported in in steam networks in the city for central heating systems or city heating systems and of course electricity. But so the economy is not just based on the size of these facilities, but also about how
To make an economic use of the of the heat and the steam and other electricity, so these are determining elements. But maybe Peter can explain more about their facility. Yes, yes, I can. Yes, what Herman said, we in.
In fact, now we have the the largest plant in the world with 1.4 million tons a year. That's
and also we.
We co-incinerate also 100,000 tons of sewage sludge. That's from our neighbour next door. That's the wastewater treatment plant. So in total, we have a capacity. If you calculate it in in a day, we talk about 4,400 tons per day.
We also had a discussion when we started designing this plant. What should be the optimal optimal size? And what you can see if you look at all the plants that that have been recently recently built is that the larger plant you build, the lower cost you have. That is, yeah, just a matter.
of specific investment cost.
A plant twice as large doesn't cost twice that twice the price. So you see a lot of smaller installation. They have very
高投資成本，佢哋 go up to maybe 800 or
€1,000 per ton capacity per year. That's the calculation we make, and in our case, you talk about the half of it, €500.
Europe a ton per year, so there is a big economy of scale. Also, when you look at it, if you look at, for example, what Herman mentioned, the energy contracts we have, we produce around one million megawatt hours of electricity. That's one percent of the total usage.
或，The Netherlands。
So we are also an important power producer. We have we have better contracts than you when you have very small installation, because you bring a lot of volume to the to the market. So that's that's very important. And of course, we delivery of heat to district heating.
或Steam networks， and that works even better that for for the economy.
但係，investment of these installation， that's the yeah big part of the
呀，the cost for
for waste-to-energy plants.
Any other question from members?
啊，會智慧議員。Thanks. Ah, I just want to ask, you know, say um in the early parts of the speech, you know, say saying that um.
the the incinerator in in Netherlands say has good performance. Can you explain more on say what do you mean by good performance in what aspects?
on the other hand, I would like to know, would there be any other measures? Because a lot of time when we are talking about using the incinerator or we are talking about the waste management strategies, it will be a combination of both incinerating and also waste reductions.
and other no say measures, so I just want to know no say how that different parts or different strategies no say can form a mix to to have no say a comprehensive no say waste management schemes at the same time.
if。
One派say reduction of waste can achieve no say a good level of standards. Then no say you may come to no say another problems that no say there may not be enough no say waste for you to incinerate.
所以唔會 say，how can you唔會 say manage唔會 say the sort of唔會 say um opposite唔會 say direction or唔會 say opposite唔會 say goals to assure then唔會 say the investment and also the policy the waste management policy will have a good mix for the countries.
They import waste from other countries. Yeah, I know that, but I just want to know, no say the the the key issues on here.
我 leave 問題 about good performance to Peter, but about the waste management strategies.
The Netherlands has 80% recycling of the waste. So we produce 60 million tons. 80% is recycled. It's material recycling. So the material, the metals and and and and and
all these and and and organics and so on is really recycled. So, eighty eighty eight zero percent recycling.
17% waste of energy.
And we have about two per cent of landfilling, even less than two per cent of landfilling. So landfilling used to be also in the Netherlands, of course, the main way of treatment of the waste. Nowadays, it's only of less than two per cent. So one two million tons of waste is.
是 landfill in about 20 landfills, but it's not a very profitable business anymore.
The strategies, the way we operated was by making landfilling the most expensive way of treatment. It's also, but Mr. Lee can explain it's.
We introduced a landfill tax in 1995. We gradually increased it, like UK does. And in 2012, we revoked the landfill tax because no landfill or hardly any waste was landfilled, and the income for the
財政部是約零。
And they were afraid that the old landfills would be excavated for incineration, and that they had to pay. The treasury department had to pay for the land, the waste which had been landfilled. So this has been revoked. So at the moment, we only have a
landfill ban of about 40 waste streams, no landfill tax anymore because we reached the level we wanted to. So
recycling and reuse and prevention, of course, those are the targets. And also in European Framework Directive, it's incorporated this waste hierarchy in the European Framework Directive. And we do have an
cess capacity for incineration at this moment. This was this was caused because
政府在2003年決定跳過規劃。
We used to have a planning of waste to energy facilities in order to avoid an excess capacity.
但係， in 2003， this was liberalised， so anybody who wants to start a facility
They're free to do it as long as they meet the requirements for land use and for the emissions and so as they can acquire a license.
所以我們有 excess capacity，但係呢，係完全係啲廠主嘅風險。所以如果佢哋唔能夠有足夠嘅廢棄物，噉佢哋就會
maybe go broke.
所以它哋嘅風險，它哋唔係被政府支持嘅，唔再用。以前喺規劃期，我們支持呢啲設施，而家係自由市場，所以唔支持佢哋，佢哋可以進口廢物，只要佢哋。
meet the requirements of a recovery facility, so are one criterion of the European Framework Directive.
所以我們有混合策略， waste of energy 是一個重要的，因為我們不想要填埋廢棄物，或者我們想要減少數量和 divert 作為可能。
The Netherlands is not suitable for landfilling. The Netherlands is like Hong Kong, a very densely populated country. It is we have limited space and we don't want to use it for landfilling.
所以， waste of energy is an important element. And if you look at the statistics of the EU,
EU member states who have a large incineration capacity also have high recycling rates, while countries who have low incineration rates have also high landfill and low recycling rates, and that's not coincidence. It's because
誒。
當你説廢氣能源是的的minimum標準， for treating municipal solid waste。
你有也一個最低價門費，for that，and at that time，recycling pays。
So many activities for recycling are cheaper than waste of energy or the the landfilling with high landfill taxes. But at the moment, as he said, we do not have a tax anymore. It's just landfill bans and.
There is an enormous economic space for recycling activities, and that's our strategy.
我我just one follow say，因為It's interest，It's interesting for me to to heard that to hear that no say we can make incinerating no say be a business。Am I am I wrong in?
be a business because you say you introduce market mechanism and you find some way to get private investor to build incinerator. So can you tell me something? You say how can you? Because in Hong Kong we are talking about that must be a government project.
to do incinerating， and how can we no say achieve no say from from our thinking then no say well to do incinerating must be a government project and then no say you you tell me no say we can make it as a business and then that that that interest me a lot. tell me something more about that. Well, the main
Main instrument in that was the used to be the landfill tax. Yes. Because we had landfill tax, the highest level we reached was 110 euros a ton, landfill tax.
所以，那 was excluded excluding the the operational costs. So landfilling would be about 130 euros a ton.
誒。
So at that time, waste of energy is very profitable because waste of energy plants in the Netherlands, the the newest contracts.
Are being signed at about 60 euros a ton for waste to energy, and they need to have. But I think Peter can can go more in detail about that. You need to have good contracts for electricity, and you need to have good contracts for your steam. Otherwise
你唔可以pay it，所以我諗，The facility in Amsterdam，The newest one，會有About half of the income，close to half of the income from the energy yield。
and the other income is from the gate fee，so that's the model。
Either to have high landfill taxes, landfill costs, by that that that incineration is.
competitive。
Or and the Neder and the way it's done in the Netherlands nowadays is have a landfill ban, so you're not allowed to landfill. So you have to look for other outlets. The and the only option for residual waste
is waste energy.
And Mr Simos, you have anything to?
tell our members.
Yes, there was also the question about performance earlier. Shall I start with this one? Yeah, you wanted to know where we are. Yeah.
where we perform very very good.
There are two, or maybe three things to mention, because that's the efficiency, that are the emissions and the materials that we also recover from from our process. First, what we are famous on is because we we talk about high efficiency waste to energy plant. Our newest plant.
has an electrical efficiency of over 30%.
So our and that means that from each ton of waste that we get into our plant, we can produce around 850 kilowatt hours of electricity.
And yeah, that's much higher than yeah the the average in in Europe because the the efficiency when you calculate it is around between 15 and 20 percent.
new newer plants that build now have 25% efficiency, so that is a very big step.
that that we made and even last year the figures from last year 2012 we reached an average efficiency of 31.2% and that's the net efficiency so the electricity that we put on the grid.
materials，because we said this new line is new lines are built for recovery not only as for energy but also from materials，because when you look at our process we we also have materials that come out of our our plant，talk about bottom ash you talk about fly ash and all these
materials.
And there, we also said we want to.
make sure that we can, sorry.
reuse all these materials as much as possible and.
what you see is what we achieve. That only one percent of the materials coming out of this plant we cannot reuse. All the other materials are reused in other processes.
The main stream, that's bottom ash, that's 20% of what's going in, is also coming out because that's inert material that and that are metals, that are stone and glass and sand, they are all reused.
mainstream road construction materials, but also we have now quite advanced sorting after incineration installations to get more metals and also the non-ferrous metals that are the valuable metals out of the out of this stream. So last year we also got around thirty thousand tonnes.
of these these metals back from from the waste, so that's also yeah that's where we achieve very very well, and then of course the the emissions and that's also good to mention what I what I started with is that we said okay we want to do it better.
and we also put that more or less in the tender documents for the new plant. When we made the design for the plant, we brought this.
你put it in tender documents.
We didn't say to the market who had to supply the flue gas systems. This is the waste incineration directive. These are the requirements from the EU or the Netherlands. Now we said we are used to. These are our standards. This is what we operate for the last twenty years. They are very low, and these are your guarantee levels. You have to be.
make sure that you are lower than that, otherwise we don't choose you as the as the contractor for for this system. So.
It was quite some discussions with with all the suppliers of the materials, but they agreed and they also succeeded again to go even lower. So, yeah, that was also yeah for for Amsterdam very important that we.
said we want to go lower.
That's about performance, little bit about the cost price. I can make a small breakdown. What Herman already said.
We had last year a turnover of 180 million euros.
and when you look at it, it's
120 million euros is coming from the gate fee, but 50 million euros is coming from the sales of electricity and and heat.
And then, ten million euros is for the materials that we.
We see that that the trend is that especially that in the Netherlands, because also because of this this tendering and this overcapacity, is that the gate fee is dropping a little bit. But you see also that the materials are growing. Yeah, the cost price of these materials are rapidly increasing. So that
So there's also for us a lot of effort to get more materials from from our processes back to yeah to to optimise also our economic.
performance。
Professor Arena， yes, I would like just to confirm some of the observation made so far. In particular, I believe that you highlighted the importance of the communication.
誒。
with the people, in order to obtain.
Possible acceptance of the plant. What is really important is to organise a correct, continuous and transparent information.
And one of the aspect that you can you could use is that Peter just mentioned.
I mean about the possibility to go lower than the existing limits. For instance, in a certain plant close to Naples, which is a very large plant, seven hundred kilotons per year.
那有非常大嘅可用率，多過90%，和非常好嘅熱能效率，28%，similar to to that in Netherlands。
the the limits for Italian limits for any emission which are the lowest in the world because that of European Community.
has been reduced for a factor of four. For instance, dioxin limits is not the legal limit is not 0.1, but 0.025. The same for heavy metals and the same for nanoparticles.
The results of the plant in these two years is very, very lower than this. I mean, for dioxin is zero point zero zero eight. I mean, another factor of four lower than the accept the limit.
所以，啲人 verify 係喺三 year， 有冇 overcome the limit in any days？
And now the situation is strange because there are some environmental opposition against a new plant, but people that live close to the plant want to make it larger.
因為佢哋見到嗰個工廠運作，同埋環境污染係絕對唔係。
誒。
absolutely necessary.
在這這框架，我會想建議你另一個重要的 aspect。
That related to.
The correct waste management planning. I prepared personally the waste management for the Campania region, which is a region with Naples city and some other very crowded cities.
那已經被歐洲聯盟接受兩年了。
It's important. I indicated a separation collection rate of 50%. Please take in mind that the recycling rate is a thing,s separation collection rate is another thing,s because I can have a rate for separate collection, but the amount of material that is effectively recycled.
其實， is a
絕對低，我
only 50 kilogrammes to treat by thermal treatment or by landfill, because you have to consider also the residues of recycling chain that in general, in average in Europe, are between 20 and 28 percent.
所以如果你有個 separate collection rate 五十五%，你 need probably to to have a plant for a seventy five percent seventy kilograms of each one hundred kilograms。我唔知 if if it's clear。That's important because when I prepare the waste management planning for Nepal, Syria。
我提出呢個情況。
But has not been accepted by the local government, but by the European Community, yes. Now the situation is that the plant in Naples works very well, two thousand tons per day. But even though the separate collection in average in Campania is more than forty-two percent.
one of the highest in Italy.
The residue of a recycling chain and the other material imposes the necessity to move about one me one thousand tons per day outside of Italy to burn it.
所以，這 confirm 了 necessity of adequate waste management for the size of the plant.
That's important as our experience. I would like to.
suggest you to take it into account.
Doctor Kenneth Chen。
嗱。
回香港去 advise on waste management and waste to energy facilities and so on. I work at Baptist University. Suppose you're attending that conference, so thank you very much.
was unable to attend the conference given my work here. Anyway, good to see you. A number of questions here. Obviously, you noticed that in Hong Kong we are dealing with a very serious problem, which is the Nimby syndrome, not in my backyard syndrome.
what you see as business opportunities turn out to be something socially undesirable to many neighbourhoods in Hong Kong. Now, of course, on the one hand, it's great to hear that people in the Netherlands or people in different parts of the world are welcoming these facilities and seeing them as
雞子會落金蛋或者something like that，但not in the case of Hong Kong。just wondering what exactly it took to convince
the people to buy in. More specifically, as a political scientist by training, I wonder whether people are responding more to performance data.
science and technology， or people responding more to incentives， particularly financial incentives。 They are telling them that， hey， your bills will be cut by twenty percent。
或你的税費會被減百分之三十，或當地政府會 stop。
charging you people on facilities, tennis courts, swimming pools and this sort of things. What exactly are people responding to more effectively in order to sort of accept that sort of facilities, given the high standards that you you've been talking about? I'm not I'm not questioning the science and technology. I'm just wondering how we convince people.
people to buy in such ideas, and my second question is with the respective, perhaps roles and expectations from your perspective regarding the European Union, the national governments as well as the regional authorities, because I understand the EU is pretty complicated, involving 27 now going up to 28 countries.
with Croatia joining very soon. You mentioned briefly about the role of the European Union being the regulator.
你 laying down stringent criteria or standards in terms of directives and regulations, but I suppose at the end of the day, you would need a lot of help from the government, at national level as well as the local level. I just wonder what sort of, what specific help or assistance you've been getting from these various levels of authorities. And last but not least.
given the fact that there are 27 EU member states, or
56 in the United States of America. Surely there are successful experiences, but how about those less successful experiences or episodes that you might like to share with us here in Hong Kong, so that we can have a little bit more sort of comparative and balanced way of learning both success stories plus the less successful ones as well. The three general questions.
Do forgive my ignorance. Just ask you very big questions because I'm very interested to learn more about about your experiences. And also, chair, if I if I may, if if our guests happen to have some information in any forms and you'd like to share with the panel, I would be very interested in having information later on as well. Thank you. Yeah, definitely, we would.
Welcome. There any more further information in print or booklet form format from you that could help us to further our understanding on incineration versus other types of waste management. And yes, our expert incentive at the very initial stage to persuade.
People to accept incineration. Well, maybe.
啊，啊，都係買單，買。
comments first, what motivates people to accept? Of course, we had our share of nimbie as well.
Even we had our share of bananas. Built absolutely nothing anywhere near anybody. That's more a British phrasing.
especially after we had this crisis in 1989 with one of the incinerators polluting the meadows next to and milk containing dioxins and so on.
所以第一新 ones to be built right after it, they had some opposition, especially the one in Alkmaar. It's north of the Netherlands and where a lot of it's an agricultural area, and the farmers were afraid that the these facility would
harmed their crops and their income and so on. So
There were contracts signed between the initiator, the builder of the facility, and the farmers that if they would have any loss in their crops or quality, they would be compensated. Moreover, a lot of bio monitors were.
installed very number of plants for different of the pollutants. There was a committee installed with neighbours, farmers and so on who looked into the performance of these plants.
所以呢個plant had some lawsuits, but it was in the end it was built, it was constructed, and during first years of operation, it was heavily well, it was very critically followed, but in the end.
所以， nowadays， I think this committee doesn't exist anymore in Alkmaar， because nobody's interested， because。
and these facilities like the one in Amsterdam.
They have a very open also attitude. They have staff specially employed for groups of schoolchildren and so on, and a lot of delegations from abroad, of course, to have tours on their facility. Not one.
Not just the one in Amsterdam, but also all the other facilities do this, because this is you have to show it every day that you are doing a good job. So this first one was really the difficult, most difficult one, because it was built just and licensed in the period of the.
turmoil of this, so this one was.
After this one, also these facilities learned that they should have. They start communicating with the NGOs and with the the neighbours about these facilities before they submit an application for a license. So don't put them in.
defence, but start this these negotiations and start the communication even before you you submit the application, and that's the common way it's been done. And some of the authorities are thinking that these NGOs
taking over their position because they are negotiated between the NGOs which have these their own engineers who know a lot about these techniques.
所以，before they submit an application, they have already reached a sort of agreements.
with the the with the NGOs and the application of licence is more or less a formality.
所以那係一種處理方法，所以有個好嘅溝通，我諗彼得可以講得更多，關於呢個，可以講得更多，關於呢個，關於歐洲聯盟。
One of the major pieces of legislation in Europe on treatment of waste is the new Waste Framework Directive, which urges that you meet 50% recycling of household waste, municipal waste.
and seventy percent recycling of construction and demolition waste.
also that you have to reduce.
The amount of landfilling of biodegradable materials in the year 2016 or 2020 depends on the countries. They are only allowed to landfill 35% of the biodegradable fraction based on data of 1995. So in fact
Because the growth in between from one thousand, nine hundred and ninety five till now, it's a very small fraction which are allowed to landfill of the biodegradable. So it's heavily stimulated by the European Commission and the European Union to move to divert from landfilling to increase recycling.
And also to engage in waste energy. There are some, a lot of countries. There, I can show a graph of the European Union, and there are a lot of countries from Greece to Poland and Latvia and Lithuania and so on.
and who have very bad performance, who still landfill 90, 95% of their wastes, so not meeting
The targets, but these countries will face heavily heavy fines, because when you're not meeting the targets, the Commission will start an investigation, and then you're sentenced by the European Court, and you have to pay high fines. Also Greece.
which has already some problems with the economy. So this is Europe is really looking into it and starts to stimulate. There is a difficult difficulty with implementation of these guidelines, especially these directives, especially in Eastern European new member states. But
They're moving on as well. Poland, for instance, is already has passed Greece in in their waste management performance and many other countries. So, it's so the European
Commission is stimulating this policy as well.
Can I add something about community? Sure. Could could we
Give the priority to the professor families first, because he raised your hand already. Thank you very much.
誒。
First, with regard to making the community to accept the place, there should be effort and an expenditure on making the plant look very good.
In Vienna, you know the Spitalau project is done so well that is now a tourist attraction. If you go to the web of Vienna and you say what should I visit, they will tell you the palace and this and then they will say the Spitalau incinerator. And if you go there, you pay I think some like eighty.
€20 to go in, you know, it's a privilege. So spending, spending, and it doesn't take much. In Milan, there was a incinerator to be refurbished, and there was a lot of opposition, and architects were brought in, and I think it cost an extra 5%.
which can be a considerable expenditure, and now it's kind of a jewel in let's say in in a particular area. This is let's say to provide, like you said, swimming pools. They're provided year-round, promenades.
Visitor centre where the children can go. We have that in many U.S. incinerator waste energy plants. We call them to distinguish crematoria and other incinerators.
係。
所以，那可以做。可以也做。
Monetary privileges where electricity can be made available to the community, which more of
close to there.
Provided a lower cost, you know. Another thing, the climate in in Hong Kong in the summer can get very hot, so you could provide you could use the low steam, the low pressure steam of the plant to provide cooling to chilled water, which can be provided.
Sounds difficult, but it's been done. For instance, in in in Brasilia, with district heating. Cool. The second question was, can the government do something? Oh, yes, it can do a lot. The government. And where we see in the United States more waste to energy is where state governments provided measures. For instance, call it.
可再生能源，like solar energy, sun wind energy. Other states don't care, nothing happens. A good example with regard to the government role is China, the mainland China. You know, next door neighbour, that they have gone from 30 plants to 103 plants in something like 80.
十幾年。
And how they did it? It's not because they put money there, but they provided certain incentives. For instance, one of the incentives, very good, is they provided a thirty dollar
Equivalent credit for for power generated from a waste to energy plant versus power generated from a power plant. That thirty dollars can make a lot difference. There's some other measures. Since you are political scientist, I will send you a thesis of my student who is Chinese from Shanghai who wrote a thesis about why.
何達？的措施，的政府在中國提供，到，到幫助，廢棄能源。
Dr. Lee Post。
To add a little bit more to what Herman said, really, but from a kind of UK context, what we found was each of the facilities. When it's under development, we have these liaison groups during the construction phase. So people, members of the public, people who live nearby to the facilities, were very much actively asked to come along and participate and find out exactly what goes on.
And it was quite noticeable that during the construction phase they do attend, and then during operation, as we move into operation, they start to drift away because they realise actually this is not such a bad thing. It's a good thing, you know. It's positive. It does good good things.
And also on the visitor centre side of things, a lot of the facilities will have a full-time education worker, who's normally a teacher, whose whole job is to bring in school classes, to work with local primary schools, senior schools, to actually do education around waste awareness, waste reduction, and kind of working from that perspective. Because always the best ways to work on the children, and that affects the adults, of course. So and then.
大部份的的的基礎設施成本會被關聯到那個遊客中心。那個遊客中心會有互動的東西在那裡，去實際理解如何廢棄物管理和減少廢棄物等，可以有巨大的影響在人們身上。另外，透明度在資訊環繞廠區的方面，在數據方面，觀點是。
Everything should be online. Everything should be accessible, so the people can go online and get real time data virtually to see how the plant. What's going up the chimney? You know, they know exactly what's happening, so they can feel comfortable in terms of how the plant is performing. And I think this gives confidence to people, and people realise that the plant is tightly regulated, it's very well performing.
And it's kind of my plant, and I can my children can go there and they can get lessons about waste management, environmental things, and I think that kind of encourages and develops a kind of a completely different ethos associated with the plant.
And any more question from members?
Okay, in that case, I'll let me extend my thanks again to our expert group attending the conference in Hong Kong and kindly allocate this time slot to brief our members on your good practices and expertise and.
definitely I would welcome the further information from you in any sort of format to help out better understanding on the incineration and other forms of waste management. So thank you again.
掹曬隻枱面。